SOFTWARE ENGINEER

GULBALA SALAMOV

I am a Java enthusiast software developer. I am passionate about using modern Java 11 with Spring I am positive minded, flexible individual enjoying working in both my own initiative and team and always follow best practices to improve myself.

MAJOR ACHIEVEMENTS

- Certified by the Association of Payment and Money Institutions of Turkey as one of most successful graduate in Java Spring Fintech Bootcamp (2022)
- Worked on €2.5M project funded by the European Research Council (ERC) as Developer & Researcher (2021)
- Published Android Mobile Programming book in Java, recommended textbook in Turkish universities in 2017

ABOUT AND CONTACT

Nationality: Turkish, Azerbaijan E-mail: g.salamov@gmail.com Phone: +90 536 710 2202

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gulbalasalamov/

GitHub: www.github.com/gulbalasalamov

MAIN SKILLSET & ABILITIES

- Java 8,11
- Android
- Spring, Spring Boot, Hybernate, Data JPA
- JUnit5, Integration Test
- SQL, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- HTML / CSS
- Design Pattern & Code Organization
- Version CS (Git, GitHub)
- OutSystems (NoCode -LowCode)
- OAS & Swagger
- Adobe XD
- Additional Tools (Jira, Confluence, Slack, Teams)
- Research & Development, Technical Writing

PROFESSIONAL TRAININGS

- Java Spring Fintech Bootcamp Aug 2022
 The Association of Payment & Electronic Money Institutions of Turkey (TÖDEB)
- Java Spring Enterprise Application Development Jul 2022
 Udemy
- Swagger and Open API Specification Feb 2022
 Udemy

CAREER SUMMARY

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER & TECHNICAL WRITER

eSystems Nordic | Feb 2022 - July 2022 | FINLAND

- Building backend&frontend components in OutSystems
- Creating high-quality documentation
- Research, write, edit and revise content

JR. SOFTWARE DEVELOPER & RESEARCHER University College London | Apr 2019 - Jun 2020 | U.K.

- Maintained data collection app using Java and Android
- Designed and implemented new mobile apps
- Prepared technical documentations
- Contributed to academic research and workshops

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER & RESEARCHER INTERN State University of New York | Jun 2017 - SEP 2017 | U.S.A

Built interactive prototypes for university mobile app
 Collaborated closely with university IT department to conduct user research

JR. SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT CONSULTANT

SIP | Sep 2015 - SEP 2016 | AZERBAIJAN

- Communicated with clients and verified their needs
- Simplified complex technical concepts with high-quality prototypes, use cases and diagrams
- Prepared technical documentations
- Built e-commerce web sites using CMS and LMS

EDUCATION

HACETTEPE UNIVERSITY, TURKEY

PhD in Computer Education, 2030 (expected graduation)

SWANSEA UNIVERSITY, U.K.

MSc in Computer Science, 2016

MIDDLE EAST TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY, TURKEY

BSc in Computer Education & Instructional Technology, 2014

LANGUAGE CERTIFICATIONS

- TURKISH NATIVE
- AZERBAIJAN NATIVE
- ENGLISH ADVANCED (IELTS: 6.5)
- RUSSIAN ELEMENTARY